

# **Daniel Newbold**

Senior Full Stack Engineer - React/React Native, Angular, Vue, Node, PHP, Python, AWS, Azure

Address: 4056 Windsor Ln, Milton, FL 32571

**Email:** newboldd537@gmail.com

I am a senior full-stack developer with more than 10 years of extensive experience in web application development using multiple languages and frameworks. I am proficient in all stages of application development including requirement analysis, designing, coding, testing, and debugging.

As a Senior Fullstack Developer, I am highly proficient in both front-end and back-end technologies, and I have worked on various projects, ranging from small-scale applications to complex enterprise solutions.

#### Technical Specifications:

- ® Backend Node.js (Nest, Express), PHP, Laravel, Symfony, Django, Flask, Golang, .Net, Java, Python
- © CMS Frameworks Wordpress, Webflow, Wix, Squarespace, Drupal, Shopify
- APIs Restful API, Social Media API (Facebook, Google, Instagram) Twilio, SendGrid, Payment Gateway (Paypal, Stripe)
- Databases MySQL, Redis, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Supabase Elasticsearch
- DevOps AWS, Azure, Gitlab, CI/CD, GCP, Kubernetes

My strong technical skills and business experience give me the ability to communicate with and create alignment between developers, product owners, stakeholders, and executives.

Please contact me at any time when it is convenient for you to discuss further.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Whitepages

July 2019 - October 2022

#### Senior Lead FullStack Engineer - Frontend and Backend

- Worked on a development team to create new, awesome features for millions of users
- Lead the developers of development team to extend the functionality and performance of applications. Provided third level assistance and support on developed applications.
- Provided ongoing feedback to upper management on the current status of projects
- Provided architectural leadership by leading design, implementation, code reviews and drive teams to the highest standards
- Developed UI, management layer and Services, and APIs

Contix April 2015 - April 2018

# Senior FullStack Engineer - React/Angular/Vue, PHP/Laravel, Python, AWS

- Build and maintain REST APIs used by our internal tools to gain access to the data
- Assist project/program/product managers, providing technical information to do project scoping and scheduling
- Work with the operations team to improve monitoring on all backend systems and APIs
- Continuously design, develop and deploy backend services with focus on high availability, low latency and scalability
- Collaborate with developers across product and services teams to integrate with backend APIs

**OpenArc**May 2011 - June 2014

#### Senior Frontend Developer

- Build applications using a variety of languages to include
- Familiarity with common patterns in building distributed systems, such as service registration and discovery, routing, load balancing and circuit breakers
- Supports Sales team with product modifications and engineering

### **Created using Resumonk - Online Resume Builder**

- Think through complex problems and work with a team to implement real-world solutions
- Build web applications that work equally well on desktop and mobile devices

#### **EDUCATION**

## **University of West Florida**

July 2012 - December 2016

Bachelor of Architecture (BArch), Computer science

# Florida Atlantic University

July 2006 - November 2010

Master of Computer Applications (MCA)

#### SKILLS

My skill sets include:

- Frontend React(Next.js), Angular, Vue(Nuxt.js), Typescript, Gatsby.JS, Tailwind CSS
- ⊚ Backend PHP, Laravel, Node.js (Nest, Express), Symfony, Python, Django, Golang, Rust
- ⊚ CMS Frameworks Wordpress, Webflow, Drupal, Shopify
- @ APIs Restful API, Social Media API (Facebook, Google, Instagram) Twilio, SendGrid, Payment Gateway (Paypal, Stripe)
- Databases MySQL, Redis, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch
- Programing Language Javascript, PHP, Ruby, Python, Golang, C/C++, C#(.NET)